“水晶湖营地1958年”
杰呢？
Where's Jay?
马铃薯烤了多久？
你是怎么做到的？
How long were those potatoes under the fire?
How'd you do that?
- 会被别人看到的
- 不可能
-Somebody will see!
-No way.
玛丽安的吻功和我的一样高明吗？
-Does Maryann kiss as good as I do?
-How would I know?
我怎么知道？
你哦…
- 你说我们的感情很特别
- 我说的是真心话
-You said we were special.
-I meant everything.
- 不可以这样
- 别这么保守
-That's not allowed.
-Come on.
别这样，男人又不是石头做的
Come on. A man is not made out of stone.
有人来了
Somebody's there!
我们什么都没做，我们只是玩玩…
We weren't doing anything.
We were just messing a--
拜托
拜托，不要！
Please, don't!
不！
No!
片名：《十三号星期五》
编剧：维多米勒
制片、导演：席恩康宁汉
“6月13日
星期五，现代”
嗨，小女生…
对不起，你是小男生
Hi, girl. Excuse me! Hi, boy.
你会讲英文吗？
You speak English?
How far is it to Camp Crystal Lake?
这里离水晶湖营地有多远？
有这么远吗？
That far?
Okey-dokey. See you later.
好，回头见
现在是6月13日星期五
七点零一分
It's 7:01 on Friday the 13th of June.
我是大维
各位懒骨头，可以起床了
This is Big Dave and it's time for you
lazybones to get out of bed.
今天是水晶湖的黑猫日
It's black-cat day in Crystal Lake.
“高杰奇案录”
我大概看了82遍
I must have seen that Kojak 82 times.
请问一下，水晶湖营地离这里有多远？
Excuse me. How far
is Camp Crystal Lake from here?
有多远，伊诺斯？差不多20英里吧
What is it, Enos? About 20 miles?
- 差不多
- 血腥营地？
-About that.
-Camp Blood?
- 那个地方又重新开放啦？
- 祝你好运
-They're opening that place again?
-Lots of luck.
- 我可以坐公车去吗？
- 不太可能
-Can I get a bus or something?
-Not likely.
伊诺斯，你不是要去十字路口吗？
You going out to the crossroads, Enos?
What about a lift? That would be halfway.
你可以载她一程，反正差不多在半路上
没问题，楚蒂
小妹，咱们走吧
No sweat, Trudy. Okay, kid, let's move it.
- 我叫安妮
- 好，安妮，咱们走
-Name's Annie.
-All right, Annie, let's go.
营地其他的女生也像你一样漂亮吗？
All the girls up there
gonna look as good as you?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 你要去血腥营地，对吧？
- 劳夫，该死的，滚开
-You're going to Camp Blood, ain't you?
-Goddamn it, Ralph, get out of here!
- 别烦她了
- 你此番有去无回
-Leave people alone!
-You'll never come back!
闭嘴，劳夫
Oh, shut up, Ralph!
那里被诅咒了
It's got a death curse!
这小子真是个末日先知，对吧？
He's a real prophet of doom, ain't he?
上车吧，小姐
Climb up, miss.
他的胡言乱语让你的老板伤透脑筋
He's causing problems enough
for your boss with all that talk.
这家伙真是个讨厌鬼
Goddamn nuisance.
- 他有没有跟你说了些什么？
- 谁？
-He tell you anything?
-Who?
你老板，史帝夫克斯帝
Your boss. Steve Christy.
他说我要帮50个小孩和十个工作人员烧菜
I'll be cooking for 50 kids and 10 staff.
来这里露营的多半是贫民区的小孩
-Campers will mostly be inner-city children.
-No, I mean about what happened.
不，我说的是当年发生的事
没有
No.
你一定有事瞒着我
Come on. There's something
you're not telling me.
我劝你现在就辞职
-Quit. Quit now.
-Quit? Why would I want to quit?
辞职？为什么？
水晶湖营地被诅咒了
Camp Crystal Lake is jinxed!
连你也说这种话
Terrific. Not you too. You sound
like your crazy friend back there.
你和刚刚那个疯子劳夫差不多嘛
也许吧
克斯帝有没有告诉你
Well, maybe. Did Christy tell you about
the two kids murdered in '58?
58年那两个年轻人被杀的事？
57年那个男孩淹死的事？
还有当年那些火灾？
Boy drowning in '57? A bunch of fires?
警方根本查不出是谁干的好事
Nobody knows who did any of them.
1962年他们打算再度开张，结果水有问题
In 1962, they were going to open up.
The water was bad.
克斯帝迟早会落得像他爸妈一样
Christy will end up like his folks:
Crazy and broke.
变成个一文不明的疯子
他用了一整年整修那个地方，
至少花了两万五千元
He's been up there a year fixing up that
place. Must have dropped $25,000.
他这是何苦？你去问问别人就知道
And for what? Ask anybody.
- 辞职吧！
- 我不能
-Quit!
-I can't.
你们这些傻小孩自以为无所不知
Dumb kids. Know-it-alls.
就像我的┡一样，脑袋里都装石头
Just like my nieces. Heads full of rocks.
你真是个典型的美国人
-You're an American original.
-I'm an American original.
我真是个典型的美国人
傻孩子，至少我不怕鬼
-Dumb kid.
-At least I'm not afraid of ghosts.
- 孩子，保重
- 没问题，谢谢你载我一程
-Take care of yourself.
-No sweat. Thanks for the lift.
玛西，你说水晶湖营地
Hey, Marcie. You really think
there'll be other gorgeous women...
会不会有其他像你这样标致的妞儿？
...at Camp Crystal Lake besides yourself?
奈德，你满脑子只有性爱吗？
-Is sex all you ever think about, Ned?
-Hey, no. No. Absolutely not.
不…绝对不是
有时候我会想到跟女生接吻
Sometimes I just think about kissing women.
“欢迎光临水晶湖营地”
- 过来帮个忙吧
- 没问题
-You wanna give me a hand over here?
-Sure.
艾莉丝！我要把这棵树桩挖起来
Alice! I wanna get this tree stump out.
你们过来拉这边，艾莉丝！
Get on this side, you pull
on that side. Alice!
我来了
Coming.
- 好极了，我是史帝夫克斯帝
- 我是杰克
-That's great. I'm Steve Christy.
-Jack.
- 我叫玛西
- 我是奈德鲁宾斯坦
-Marcie
-Ned Rubinstein.
欢迎来到水晶湖营地
这是艾莉丝
Welcome to Camp Crystal Lake.
This is Alice.
史帝夫，二号小木屋已经准备好了
Hi. Steve, Cabin B is all ready.
比尔呢？他把船屋整理好了吗？
-Where's Bill? Cleaning out the boathouse?
-Haven't seen him in half an hour.
我已经半个小时没看到他了
我要他开始油漆，布兰达呢？
I wanted him to start painting. Brenda?
- 你叫她整理射箭场
- 不，我要叫她去油漆
-Setting up the archery range.
-I'd rather she paint. Come on. Let's go.
大家动作快
我们不是有两个星期的时间吗？
I thought we had two weeks.
跟我来，我带你们去换衣服
Come on. I'll show you
where you can get changed.
- 我来帮你
- 谢谢
-Here, let me give you a hand with that.
-Thank you.
可以了吗？
You got it?
你很会画画
You draw very well.
谢谢，可惜时间不够
Thanks. I wish I had more time to do it.
真蠢
Oh, dummy.
- 这是你什么时候画的？
- 昨天晚上
-When did you do this?
-Last night.
- 我真是这个德性吗？
- 你昨晚是这样没错
-Do I really look like that?
-You did last night.
你很有天份
You're very talented.
你也很漂亮
You're very pretty.
这份差事真的不适合你，对吧？
This really isn't your cup of tea, is it?
有什么特别的原因吗？
Any particular reason?
这是我自己的问题，跟你没有关系
It's just a problem I have.
It's nothing personal.
- 你要走了？
- 不知道
-You wanna leave?
-I don't know. I may have to...
我也许得回加州去处理一些事情
...go back to California
to straighten something out.
别这样，再给我一次机会
Come on. Give me another chance.
再留一个星期，帮我整顿这个地方
Stay a week.
Help get the place ready.
到了周五你若去意仍坚，到时候我送你上车
By Friday, if you're not happy,
I'll put you on the bus myself.
好吧，再留一个星期，到星期五
All right. Friday. I'll give it a week.
谢了，艾莉丝
Thanks, Alice.
比尔，史帝夫想知道是不是要更多油漆
Bill? Steve wants to know
if we need more paint.
- 油漆够了，不过稀释剂不够
- 好，我告诉他
-Paint's all right. Need more thinner, though.
-Okay.
艾莉丝，其他人来了吗？
-Alice. Did the others show up?
-Yeah, everybody except that girl Annie.
大家都来了，只剩下安妮还没到
你熬得过整个夏天吗？
-Think you're gonna last all summer?
-I don't know if I'm gonna last all week.
我连熬一个星期的信心都没有
我会告诉史帝夫多拿些稀释剂来
好
-I'll tell Steve about the thinner.
-Fine.
- 你要分开列表吗？
- 对
-You want it listed separately?
-Right.
布兰达，我要你先把射箭场整理好
Brenda, I want you to
finish the archery range.
安妮一到就叫她到厨房工作
If Annie gets here, get her started
in the kitchen. Do your best.
尽力而为，知道吗？
我吃完午饭就会回来
I'll be back sometime after lunch.
待会儿要下大雨了
It's supposed to rain like hell,
so get as much done as possible.
你们加紧赶工，我不希望进度落后太多
他忘了告诉我们，镇上的人称这里为血腥营地
He neglected to mention that downtown
they call this place "Camp Blood."
搞不好这里的厕所里有蛇，湖里还有鳄鱼
Next there'll be snakes in the
outhouse and crocodiles in the lake.
不，鳄鱼都在木屋里
No, the crocodiles are in the cabins.
- 你疯啦？
- 我花式射箭手法更高竿
-Are you crazy?
-Wanna see my trick shot? It's even better.
你真不可思议
I don't believe you!
甜心，你生气时更美
You know, you're beautiful
when you're angry, sweetheart.
- 真的吗？
- 真的
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
你是来帮我还是来吓我的？
You come to help me or scare
me to death? You do that again...
你敢再来这招，我就把你钉在墙上
你说这话真性感
-...l'll tack you up on the wall to dry.
-I love that sexy talk!
嗨，我要去水晶湖营地
Hi. I'm going to Camp Crystal Lake.
我一直都想跟孩子们共事
Guess I always wanted to
work with children.
我讨厌听别人叫他们“小鬼”，
听起来好像小羊
I hate when people call them "kids."
Sounds like little goats.
但我为了追求梦想，愿意不择手段
But when you've had a dream
as long as I have, you'll do anything.
刚刚那不是通往水晶湖营地的路吗？
Hey, wasn't that the road for
Camp Crystal Lake back there?
我们最好停车
I think we better stop.
拜托
Please?
停车！拜托…
Stop, please! Please! Stop!
Please, stop!
不！…
No. No.
不
No.
大家一起来，往左边一点点…
All right, move it out. A little to the left.
Little to the left.
拉出去，往左边一点点…不…
Move it out. Move it out. Okay,
little to the left. Now-- No, no.
这样很好…很好…
Let's go. Okay. Okay. Good. Good.
如果你是冰淇淋，你要当什么口味？
If you were a flavor of ice cream,
what would it be?
洛基巧克力
-Rocky Road.
-Hey!
你吃维他命C究竟是为了什么？
What's that vitamin C
stuff do for you, anyway?
维他命C可以中和硝酸盐
Vitamin C is supposed to neutralize
the nitrates or something.
怎么了？你是不是看到什么了？
What's the matter? Do you see something?
没有…
No. Nothing.
奈德！走开
Ned! Get out of here!
我来抓你了
- 各位，准备开工了吗？
- 可以了
-Hey, you guys. Ready to go back to work?
-Yeah.
- 来吧，艾莉丝
- 救命…
-Come on, Alice.
-Help! Help!
奈德不太对劲
-Something's wrong with Ned.
-Get a life preserver!
去拿救生圈
- 他会游泳吗？
- 我不知道
-Can he swim?
-I don't know.
- 他在这附近
- 我来
-He's right around here somewhere.
-I got it.
潜下去找他
Go ahead, dive for him.
- 他在那里
- 快来救我
-There he is!
-Come on. Help me.
小心他的头
Watch his head.
- 小心他的头
- 抱住他了吗？
-Watch his head!
-Got him?
- 你会做口对口人工呼吸吗？
- 会
-Can you give mouth-to-mouth?
-Yeah.
- 天啊
- 加油，奈德
-Oh, God.
-Come on, Ned.
- 奈德
- 天啊！
-Oh, Neddy!
-Oh, Jesus Christ!
听着，对不起嘛…可以了吗？
Look, I'm sorry. I'm sorry, all right?
比尔！
Bill!
比尔，过来，快点…
Bill, come here, quick! Hurry!
- 什么事？
- 那里有一条蛇
-What is it?
-There's a snake over there.
在哪里？
Where?
- 我该怎么办？
- 杀了它
-What do I do?
-Kill it.
它说不定会咬我
It might bite.
- 你没进过丛林吗？
- 这里不是丛林
-Haven't you ever been in the woods?
-We're not in the woods.
- 比尔，你在做什么？
- 那里有一条蛇
-Bill, what are you doing?
-There's a snake.
- 我们进来干嘛？
- 别让我失望啊
-Why are we in here?
-Feet don't fail me now!
- 在那里
- 天啊
-There it is!
-Oh, God!
- 有蛇在这里我怎么睡觉？
- 没人提过这里有蛇
-I can't sleep with a snake in here.
-Nobody said anything about snakes.
- 杀了它
- 它不出来我怎么杀它？
-Kill it!
-I can't get it until it comes out.
- 叫它出来
- 要怎么叫蛇啊？
-Well, call him!
-How do you call a snake?
我把它赶出来
I'll flush him!
- 我来
- 在哪里？
-I got it.
-Where--?
- 小心
- 让我来
-Look out!
-I got him!
天啊
Oh, God.
它死了吗？
Is it dead?
不是死了就是分裂了
Either that or it's got a very short clone.
- 至少我们知道晚餐菜色为何
- 玛西…
-Well, at least we know what's for dinner.
-Marcie!
我要做沙拉
要不要多做一点大家吃？
I'm making salad. Want me
to make some for everybody?
- 好极了，我们好像还有汉堡
- 我不吃汉堡
-That would be great. There's hamburger--
-None for me.
有苹果，你会做苹果派吗？
There are apples.
Know how to make apple pie?
- 当然，没问题
- 酷啊，怎么回事？
-Sure. No sweat.
-What is going on?
可恶
Oh, shit.
- 你们是谁？
- 我们是营地辅导员
-Who are you people?
-Camp counselors. Ned is just fooling around.
奈德只是闹着玩的
- 对，我只是…
- 闭嘴，酋长
-Right, just--
-Can it, Cochise.
是史帝夫克斯帝请你们来的？
他花钱请你们胡闹？
Steve Christy hire you people?
He pay you for this?
- 好帅的摩托车
- 小子，你抽烟了？
-Nice bike.
-You been smoking, boy?
抽烟？我不抽烟，抽烟会致癌
Smoking? Don't smoke. Causes cancer.
少装糊涂，你是不是骇了？是不是哈了草？
You just get off a spaceship or something?
Colombian gold. Grass. Hash. The weed.
- 他在说什么？
- 少自作聪明
-What's he talking about?
-Don't get smart.
- 我？我这个人最笨了
- 你给我闭嘴，懂吗？
-Me? I'm as dumb as they come.
-Not another word out of you, understand?
其实我们只是在整顿这个地方，如此而已
Nothing's going on here.
We're getting the place in shape.
为什么？
For what?
警察先生，有没有什么要我们效劳的？
-Is there anything we can do to help?
-I'm looking for somebody.
- 我们很乐意帮忙
- 我在找人
- 找谁？
- 镇上的疯子劳夫
-Who's that?
-A guy named Ralph. The town crazy.
这里没有疯子
There's no crazy people around here.
我不是叫你闭嘴吗？
I told you to sit on it, Tonto. I got word
Ralph was pedaling out this way...
我听说劳夫骑车往这儿来，
打算宣扬他的“福音”
我们没看到任何人
-...spouting his gospel.
-We haven't seen anybody here.
- 这里只有我们
- 这个叫劳夫的人有危险性吗？
-Just us.
-This guy Ralph. Is he dangerous?
那个疯子每次喝醉酒就抓狂
Every time that loony gets drunk,
he gets his calling.
最后搞得我必须出庭作证让法官判他坐一周牢
I spend the morning in court,
he gets a week in jail.
二号警车，你在哪里？听到请回答
Cycle Two, where are you?
Come in, Cycle Two.
我是多夫，我在水晶湖营地，通话完毕
This is Dorf. I'm out here
at Camp Crystal Lake. Over.
多夫，回来，老大要你回镇上
Haul it back in, Dorf.
Chief wants you back in town.
收到，我马上来，通话完毕
Roger that. 10-4. On my way. Out.
千万不能让老大久等
Never keep the chief waiting.
你们这些小鬼别惹麻烦，明白吗？
You kids keep your noses clean, understand?
You'll be hearing from me if you don't.
否则我会找上门来的
我们这里可不容忍任何人为非作歹
We ain't gonna stand
for no weirdness out here.
我是上帝派来的使者，
你们留在这里只有死路一条
I'm a messenger of God.
You're doomed if you stay here.
这个地方被诅咒了，被诅咒了
This place is cursed. Cursed.
- 这里被下了死亡咒
- 你是谁？
-It's got a death curse!
-Who are you?
你想干嘛？
What do you want?
- 是上帝派我来的
- 走开
-God sent me.
-Get out of here, man!
我来警告你们，你们留在这里只有死路一条
I got to warn you.
You're doomed if you stay.
快走吧…
Go. Go!
那个八成就是劳夫
-I think we just met Ralph.
-God, what's next?
天啊，接下来还会发生什么事？
你们全都死定了…
You're doomed. You're all doomed.
- 谁喜欢吃生一点的汉堡？
- 我
-Who likes them rare?
-Me.
你们怎么吃得下？看起来好像死掉的动物
How can you guys eat that?
It looks like dead animals.
死掉的动物？
Dead animals? That's the old counselors.
You cannibals!
那些是以前的辅导员，你们这些食人族
只要比例正确就能吸收身体所需的蛋白质
If you would mix this stuff right,
you'd get all the protein you need.
可惜安妮放我们鸽子，据说她厨艺高明
Too bad Annie never showed.
She was supposed to be a good cook.
- 可别指望我们当大厨
- 女人要造反了
-Don't expect me to play chef.
-The squaws are revolting.
- 有麻烦吗？
- 不是灯泡坏了就是停电
-Trouble?
-Yeah. A bad bulb or no power.
里面看起来阴森森的
Seems a little gloomy in here.
史帝夫教过我怎么用备用发电机
Steve taught me how to use
the emergency generator.
- 镇上的供电设备很蹩脚
- 瞧他一副男子汉的模样
-Town power lines are lousy.
-Don't you love that macho talk?
备用发电机
Emergency generator.
- 要不要过来帮我一下？
- 好
-Want to give me a hand?
-Yeah.
- 等我
- 你们留下来注意汉堡
-Wait for me.
-Can you watch the burgers?
- 没问题
- 烤焦算了
-Sure.
-Burn them.
- 他会不会大惊小怪？
- 我不知道
-Think he's gonna be bent out of shape?
-I don't know.
这台发电机和我叔叔
缅因州木屋里的那台差不多
This looks almost like the one
at my uncle's cabin in Maine.
- 试试看
- 真是老古董
-Well, here goes.
-What an antique.
神行了何等大事？
Well, what hath God wrought?
哈？
Hello?
有什么事吗？
Can I help you?
哈？…
Hello? Hello?
- 跟我来
- 我来了
-Come on.
-Coming, I'm coming.
起风了，而且风向180度大转变
Wind's come up.
Shifted a good 180 degrees.
这让我想紧紧拥抱你
Makes me want to hold onto you.
- 奈德怎么办？
- 我又不爱奈德
-What about Ned?
-I don't love Ned.
- 他像个大浑球
- 奈德
-He keeps acting like such a jerk.
-Neddy!
别叫他
我还以为你想好好教训他一顿
-Don't call him.
-Thought you wanted to give him...
...one of your motherly lectures.
奈德这个人本来就是为所欲为
Look, Neddy's gonna do whatever
Neddy wants to do, you know?
暴风雨要来了，这里会被吹得七零八落
It's gonna storm. Gonna tear down
that valley like a son of a gun.
我从小就怕暴风雨
I've been afraid of storms
since I was little.
真的吗？
No. Really?
我好几次梦到自己被困在暴风雨中
I've had this dream about five or six
times where I'm in a thunderstorm...
天上下着倾盆大雨，
雨珠落地时听起来像石头一样
...and it's raining really hard. It sounds
like pebbles when it hits the ground.
我听得到，我想捂住耳朵，但是没有用
I hear it and I try to block it out
with my hands, only it doesn't work.
声音越来越大
It just keeps getting
louder and louder.
后来雨珠变成血
And then the rain turns to blood...
血流成河
...and the blood washes away
in little rivers...
后来声音就没了
...and then the sound stops.
那只是个梦
-It's just a dream.
-I know. I call it my "shower dream."
我知道，我称之为“血雨梦”
这可不是梦，快走，咱们要变成落汤鸡了
Hey, hey. This is no dream.
Come on, we're gonna get soaked.
杰克和玛西会被淋成落汤鸡
Jack and Marcie are gonna get drenched!
他们若躲起来亲热就不会
Not if they're where I think they are.
真好听
That's nice.
我想到了，我们来玩大富翁
I know what we can do.
We'll play Monopoly.
- 我最讨厌大富翁
- 我的玩法很棒的
-I hate Monopoly!
-Not the way I play it, you don't.
- 你的玩法是怎样？
- 我们来玩脱衣大富翁
-Like what?
-We're going to play strip Monopoly.
- 我来当庄家
- 你在开玩笑吧？
-I'll be the shoe.
-You have got to be kidding.
万一史帝夫闯进来怎么办？
What if Steve walks in?
- 我们网开一面，他可以不脱鞋
- 很简单的
We'll give him a handicap.
He can keep his boots on. It's easy.
你们不用付租金，用衣服来抵帐
Instead of rent, you pay clothes. Bill
can be banker. Unless he's chicken.
比尔当银行，除非他没种
若你不幸来到我开的旅馆，你就完了
Heaven help you if you land
in my hotel!
看看玛西有没有留些大麻下来
Why don't you see if Marcie
left any of that grass?
- 我的五百块筹码呢？
- 在那里，我的棋子呢？
-What happened to my 500's?
-They're there. Where's my shoe?
我可不会轻易认输
I'm not going to pass "Go"
without a glow.
我们已经帮你掷过骰子了，你排最后
We rolled for you. You're going last.
公家金库也不会把衣服还给你
Community Chest cannot
give you your clothes back.
两个六，我可以再掷一次
Double sixes! I get to roll again!
- 她好像出老千
- 你说得没错
-We're being hustled.
-I think you're right.
你真棒
You are so fine.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
我要尿尿，你压到我的膀胱了
I gotta pee.
You're lying on my bladder.
快去快回，床上没有你变得好冷
Hurry back, okay?
It's getting cold in here.
- 你会帮我留个位置吗？
- 当然
-You'll save my place for me?
-Yeah.
五
Five.
- 波罗的大道，我买了
- 那里门可罗雀
-Baltic Avenue. I'll buy it.
-No one ever lands on Baltic Avenue.
我喜欢这个颜色
I think it's a pretty color.
快点
Come on.
八
Eight.
- 波罗的大道，你欠我一只靴子
- 马上给你
-Baltic Avenue. You owe me one boot.
-Coming.
艾莉丝首先进帐
Alice draws first blood.
- 你怎么可以这样说我的脚？
- 谢谢
-That's a terrible way to talk about my feet.
-Thank you.
接下来轮谁？
Who's next?
我开始喜欢这个游戏了
You know I think I'm beginning
to like this game.
等他到我的地盘时再说吧
Wait until he lands
on my old Kentucky home.
- 还要啤酒吗？我去拿
- 我看看，是铁路
-More beer? More beer.
-Let's see. A railroad.
“离厕所40码，威利梅克制作”
Forty Yards to the Outhouse,
by Willie Makit.
小鬼，你们太逊了吧？
Come on, kids,
you can do better than that.
杰克？
Jack?
我照镜子时知道自己永远是个丑八怪
When I looked into that mirror,
I knew I'd always be ugly.
我说“小姐，你永远都这么平庸”
I said,
"Lady, you'll always be plain."
哈？
Hello?
奈德？
Ned?
你们别闹了
Hey, come on, you guys.
大概是我想像力作怪
It must be my imagination.
- 你惨了
- 可恶
-Hello.
-Shit.
我的手气真是背透了
Worst run of bad luck
since Richard Nixon.
你可以认输
You can call it quits.
你做梦，你再走两步就要脱光了
Fat chance! You're two steps
from Pacific Avenue and Skin City.
我还能说什么？
What can I say?
It's not much, but I call it home.
这个地方再怎么说也是我的狗窝
- 我去关门…
- 快拿钱
-I'll get it. I'll get it.
-Get the money.
- 天啊
- 外面风好大
-God!
-It's blowing like crazy out there.
我木屋的窗户好像忘了关
I think I left the windows
in my cabin open. Shoot!
咱们改天再玩吧
We'll have to finish this game
some other night.
讨厌，赛况才刚刚变得有趣
Just when it was getting interesting.
- 明天见
- 再见
-See you guys in the morning.
-See you.
- 晚安
-Good night.
乱死了，拿去
Look at this mess! Here.
- 你要继续玩吗？
- 我还没决定
-Were you going to go ahead with it?
-I hadn't made up my mind.
改天再玩好了
We'll have to finish
the game another night.
“餐馆”
- 史帝夫，你还要什么吗？
- 不用了，珊蒂，这样就行了
-Is there anything else you want?
-No, thanks, Sandy. I'm fine.
雨这么大，你就别走了，除非你想淹死
You can't go out in that rain.
You want to drown?
我非走不可，我营地来了六个新的辅导员
I've got to.
I've got six new counselors at camp.
他们是丛林菜鸟
They are babes in the woods,
in every sense.
只要他们懂得躲雨就不会有事
They'll be okay if they know enough
to come out of the rain.
- 我欠你多少？
- 晚上带我出去玩就好了
-Well, what do I owe you?
-Just a night on the town, Steve.
- 珊蒂，你知道我的意思
- 没问题，两块两毛五
-Come on now, you know what I mean.
-That's okay. Two and a quarter.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 这是找你的钱
- 你留着吧
-Here's your change.
-No, you keep it.
- 谢谢
- 不客气
-Thank you.
-Sure.
- 开车小心点
- 我会的
-Drive careful.
-I will.
晚安
Good night.
“餐馆”
- 嗨
-Hi.
你的车不是连城墙都爬得上去吗？
-Thought that'd go through anything.
-Not dragging a trailer.
后面挂辆拖车就不行了
能不能载我一程？
Can you give me a lift?
- 我早上再叫辅导员载我过来
- 有何不可？
-I'll have a counselor bring me back.
-Why not?
救命
Help me!
哈
Hello.
- 哈
- 在这里，快来救我
-Hello.
-Over here. Please somebody help me.
哈
Hello.
哈？
Hello?
快点来，拜托，快来救我
Come quickly, please.
Come quickly. Help.
你在哪里？哈
Where are you? Hello.
哈？
Hello?
好了
All right.
出来，这已经不好笑了
Come on out! You're not funny anymore!
一点都不好笑
It's not funny at all.
比尔
Bill.
- 发电机没事
- 我好像听到有人尖叫
-Hi. The generator is okay.
-I thought I heard a scream.
- 风这么大你怎么听得到？
- 好像是布兰达的声音
-How can you hear in that wind?
-It sounded like Brenda.
我最好去看看
I'd better look.
有人把射箭场的灯打开了
Somebody turned on the lights
at the archery range.
我什么都没看到
I can't see anything.
灯又灭了
They're off now.
我去看看
I'm gonna check it out.
比尔
-Bill. Can I come?
-Come on.
- 我可以一起去吗？
- 来吧
布兰达
Brenda!
她在哪里？
Where is she?
她一定跟杰克和玛西在一起
She must be with Jack and Marcie.
- 艾莉丝？
- 什么事？
-Alice?
-Yeah?
过来
Come here.
这是怎么回事？
What is going on?
快走
Come on!
- 杰克，开门
- 杰克
-Jack, open the door.
-Jack.
- 他们在哪里？
- 我不知道，我们走
-Where are they?
-I don't know. Come on.
布兰达？
Brenda?
玛西？
Marcie?
杰克？奈德？
Jack? Neddy?
比尔，我们应该通知别人
Bill, I think we should call someone.
若他们在开玩笑，我就要打爆他们的头
If this is a joke, I'll brain them!
我是认真的，我真的认为我们该通知别人
I'm serious.
I really think we should call someone.
锁住了
The sucker's locked.
- 钥匙呢？
- 我不知道
-Where's the key?
-I don't know.
等一下
Wait a minute.
小心
Watch out.
Be careful.
我去开灯
Let me get the light.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
线路不通，试试公用电话
It's dead. Try the pay phone.
有零钱吗？
Do you have a dime or a quarter?
没有，看看桌上有没有
No. Check the desk.
喂？
Hello?
公用电话也不通
This damn thing's dead too!
车子怎么了？
What's the matter with it?
湿了
It's wet.
我不知道
I don't know.
我们走路离开这里吧，现在就走
Why don't we just hike out of here?
Get out. Right now!
这里离最近的路口有十英里，
史帝夫很快就会回来的
It's 10 miles to the nearest crossroads.
Steve will be back soon.
我们可以开他的吉普车去求助，别担心
We can use his jeep if we need
to get help. Don't worry.
- 这一切一定有个可笑的解释
- 怎么说？
-There's some stupid explanation for this.
-Like what?
我们明天一定会笑破肚皮，我保证
We'll be laughing about this tomorrow,
I promise.
咱们别再淋雨了
Let's get out of the rain.
13号星期五还不够糟，居然碰上满月
It's not bad enough to have Friday the 13th,
we've gotta have a full moon too.
我们有做统计
We keep statistics. We have more accidents,
more rapes, more robberies...
每到满月，车祸、强暴案、
抢案、凶杀案都比平常多
...more homicides, more of everything
when there's a full moon.
人们一到满月就抓狂
It upsets people. Makes them nuts.
就算是巧合，也被你说得煞有其事
You're making science
out of coincidence.
听说劳夫今天跑去你那儿了
I hear Ralph was out your way today.
他太太紧张得要死，还好我们把他送回家了
His wife was a nervous wreck
until we got him home.
疯子劳夫跑来搅局，真是屋漏偏逢连夜雨
That's all I need,
Crazy Ralph running around.
雨快停了
Well, the rain's stopping.
不过这场雨下得还真够呛
It was a pisser while it lasted.
特尼警官，听到请回答，呼叫九号车…
Sgt. Tierney, come in.
Sgt. Tierney, Car Niner.
我是特尼
This is Tierney.
发生车祸，带油压剪到公路17英里处
Rescue squad with Jaws of Life.
Near mile-marker 17. Possible fatals.
可能有人伤亡
至少有三人被困在车上，快去
Three, maybe more, trapped.
Head on.
收到，预计15分钟后抵达
Roger. Acknowledge receipt.
Estimate arrival, 15 minutes.
- 我得让你在这里下车
- 没问题
-I have to let you off here.
-Sure.
谢谢
Thanks.
祝你好运
Good luck.
“欢迎光临水晶湖营地”
谁在那里？
Who is that?
你在这里干嘛？
What are you doing
out in this mess?
“危险，高压电”
你觉得发生了什么事？
What do you think happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
发电机大概没油了
The generator's probably out of gas.
我去看看
I'll go check it.
要不要我跟你去？
Do you want me to come with you?
你留在这里，睡一会儿吧
Why don't you stay here
and try and sleep.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
油箱是满的
Full of gas.
比尔…
发电机
Generator.
我该怎么办？
What am I gonna do?
求求你…
Please! Oh, please!
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是克斯帝家的老朋友，伍瑞斯太太
I'm Mrs. Voorhees.
An old friend of the Christys.
别哭了…
No, no. There, there.
你不冷静下来我怎么帮你？
I can't help you
if you don't calm down.
- 她死了，他也死了
- 天啊，可怜的比尔…
But she's dead and he's dead.
Oh, my God! Poor Bill! Oh, God!
- 别哭了，带我去看看
- 不…
-All right. Come on, dear. Show me.
-No. No!
没事的，我会照顾你的，
我以前也帮克斯帝家工作过
It's all right. I'll take care of you.
I used to work for the Christys.
- 天啊，这是怎么回事？
- 求求你带我离开这里
What's going on?
Help me get out of here!
这个地方阴森森的，
又加上暴风雨，难怪你会怕
It's this place and the storm.
That's why you're upset.
不…他们都死了…
No, no! They're all dead!
They're all dead!
- 好，我去看看
- 别离开我
-All right. I'll go look.
-Don't leave me!
他们会杀了你
They'll kill you too!
我不怕
I'm not afraid.
我的天啊
Oh, my Lord!
这么年轻
So young.
这么漂亮
So pretty.
什么样的禽兽才会做出这种事？
What monster could have done this?
比尔在外面
Bill is out there!
天啊，这个地方
Oh, God, this place!
史帝夫不该重新开放这个地方
Steve should never have
opened this place again!
这里发生过太多灾难
There's been too much trouble here.
你知道有个年轻男孩在这里淹死吗？
Did you know a young boy drowned?
就在那两个年轻人被杀死的前一年
The year before those two others
were killed.
都怪辅导员粗心大意
The counselors weren't paying attention!
那个男孩淹死的时候，他们正打得火热
They were making love
while that young boy drowned!
他叫杰森
His name was Jason.
事发当天我在这里工作，正忙着准备餐点
I was working the day it happened.
Preparing meals.
我以前是这里的厨师
Here. I was the cook.
应该时时刻刻都要有人注意杰森
Jason should have been watched!
Every minute!
他…
He was--
他不太会游泳
He wasn't a very good swimmer.
我们可以走了，亲爱的
We can go now, dear.
我们应该等克斯帝先生
I think we should wait for Mr. Christy.
没这个必要
That's not necessary.
我不懂
I don't understand.
救我
Help me!
救命
Help!
救命，妈咪
Help, Mommy!
Help! Help, Mommy!
我会救你的，杰森
I am, Jason.
我会的
I am.
天啊
杰森是我儿子
You see, Jason was my son.
今天是他的生日
And today is his birthday.
克斯帝先生呢？
Where's Mr. Christy?
我不能让他们重新开放这个地方，对不对？
I couldn't let them open this place again.
Could I?
这里出过那么多事
Not after what happened.
我可爱、无邪的杰森
Oh, my sweet, innocent Jason.
我的独子
My only child.
杰森
Jason.
你害他淹死
You let him drown!
你粗心大意
You never paid any attention!
看你把他害成什么样子
Look what you did to him!
杀了她，妈妈，杀了她
Kill her, Mommy. Kill her!
别让她逃走，妈妈，别让她活下去
Don't let her get away, Mommy.
Don't let her live!
我不会的，杰森…
I won't, Jason. I won't!
可恶，子弹在哪里？
Where are the goddamn bullets?
来，亲爱的
Come, dear.
我不会让你死得像杰森那么痛苦
It will be easier for you
than it was for Jason.
杀了她，妈妈，杀了她
Kill her, Mommy. Kill her!
杀了她
Kill her.
杀了她，妈妈，杀了她
Kill her, Mommy. Kill her.
她无处可躲
She can't hide.
No place to hide.
去抓她，妈妈
Get her, Mommy. Get her!
杀了她…
Kill her! Kill her.
放开我
Get off me!
不…
我帮你打了十毫克的镇定剂，没事了
Ten milligrams, Valium.
It's all right.
一切都没事了
It's all over. Everything's over.
转过身去，亲爱的
Roll over. Roll over, dear.
你爸妈已经在路上了
Your folks are on the way up.
还有人活着吗？
Is anyone else alive?
他们都死了吗？
Are they all dead?
是的
Yes, ma'am.
我的两个手下把你从湖里拖上来
Two of my men pulled you out of the lake.
We thought you were dead too.
我们也以为你也死了
你记得事发经过吗？
Do you remember very much?
那个男孩
The boy.
他也死了吗？
Is he dead too?
- 谁？
- 那个男孩，杰森
-Who?
-The boy, Jason.
杰森？
Jason?
在湖里攻击我的那个男孩，
是他把我拖进水里去的
In the lake. The one who attacked me.
The one who pulled me under the water.
我们没有找到什么男孩
Ma'am, we didn't find any boy.
但他…
But he....
那他还在那里
Then he's still there.
主演：贝西帕玛
主演：艾德琳金恩
主演：珍妮泰勒等